We are now moving to the next hands-on exercise where we are going to
下面我们要进行一个实作练习
begin with the web page that we completed in the previous exercise.
我们从上一个练习所完成的网页开始
And we are now going to introduce the bootstrap grid classes into it.
现在我们要把 Bootstrap 的网格类引入到网页中
In order to appropriately lay out the content of the pitch.
恰当地把内容布置好
In addition, we're gonna introduce some custom CSS classes into the webpage.
此外 我们还要引入一些定制的CSS类
So let's go ahead and then look at the HTML code for the web page one more time.
让我们再一次检查一下网页的HTML代码
Going into our HTML code in brackets
在Brackets中打开我们的HTML代码
we're going to see that at the top of the page in the head,
我们会看到在网页的顶端 的部分
to be have introduced the viewpoint metatag already in previously,
已经有了之前介绍的视域元标记 (viewport metatag)
so this is what provides us with the responsive behavior for our webpage.
这是网页的响应式行为的基础
Now we are gonna go in and apply the column classes to
我们现在要把纵列 (column) 类应用在
all the different divs inside the body of our webpage.
网页主体的各个不同的 div 上
Moving to the header of our page inside the body, I'm going to apply
移动到网页主体的页首处
the grid column classes to the two inner divs Inside the Jumbotron.
我要把网格系统的纵列 (column) 类应用在 Jumbotron 里面的两个内部 div 标签上
So to do that for the first div I'm going to apply a column class as
要这样做 我首先给第一个 div 添加一个 column 类
col-xs-12.
col-xs-12
12 col-sm-8.
col-sm-8
So this content is gonna be displayed
这样 这项内容在超小屏幕上显示时
in extra small devices it will occupy the entire width of the screen.
就会占据屏幕的整个宽度
But for small to large screen sizes, it is going to occupy eight columns.
但在小屏幕到大屏幕的尺寸上 它将会占据 8 个纵列
You also notice that I have another div in the jumbotron.
还有另一个 div 在这个 Jumbotron 里面
Currently, that div contains no content.
目前这个 div 没有内容
Later on I am planning to introduce a logo for our restaurant into that div.
稍后 我计划在这个 div 里面加上一个餐厅的商标
So I'm gonna leave the div empty at the moment, but I'm gonna apply the column
暂时我会把这个 div 留空 但我会先把纵列类加在这个 div 上
classes to the div so that it occupies the remaining number of columns.
让它占据剩余的纵列数
To this div I'm going to apply column classes XS 12 and
对于这个 div 我会写 col-xs-12 和 col-sm-4
SM 4 because we are left with four columns from the small to large screen sizes,
因为从小屏幕到大屏幕的尺寸上 我们还剩下4个纵列数
empty on the right-hand side of this row.
空在这一行的右边
Once we have completed this, let's now move into the divs
一旦完成了这一项 让我们翻到
in the actual content of our webpage.
网页实际内容中的 div
For each one of those divs, I have a headline and
这些 div 每一个都有标题以及
then I have the actual content.
以及实际的内容
So the headline part of it I will enclose in a smallish number of columns, but
因此对于标题部分我会分配较少的纵列数
the detailed content, I will have it occupying a larger number of columns.
而对于详细的内容 我则会让它占据更多的纵列数
So I'm going to do that by applying two different div classes for
要这样做 我会在两个 div 上
each of those columns.
应用不同的纵列类
For extra small screen sizes, I'm going to lay them out one on top of the other
对于超小尺寸的屏幕 我希望把它们上下堆叠起来
stacked, but for small to large, I'm gonna lay them out side by side.
但对于小尺寸到大尺寸的屏幕 我希望他们并列显示
So let's go and apply the column classes to those inner divs in those rows there.
让我们在这些内部 div 上面应用这些纵列类吧
For the div containing the headline, I'm going to apply column xs 12 and
对于包含了标题的 div, 我会加入 col-xs-12 和
column sm 3 in that case and for the other div I'm going
col-sm-3 而对于其他的 div, 我会
to apply the remaining columns from that.
使用剩余的纵列
Think about how I'm going to do that, all done,
想想我会怎么去做 好了 都完成了
let me repeat that for the remaining rows of.
让我对网页实际内容中剩下的行
The actual content of the webpage.
都重复这项工作
For the divs in the footer, I am going to
而对于页脚的 div, 我会
have the first div occupy three columns for
在小到大尺寸屏幕下让第一个 div
the small to large string sizes, the second div to occupy five columns.
占据 3 个纵列 让第二个 div 占据 5 个纵列
For the small to medium and large.
从小屏幕到中等屏幕直到大屏幕
And the last div to occupy the remaining for columns.
而最后一个 div 占据剩余的纵列
But for extra small I'm gonna have the first and
但在超小尺寸屏幕下我会让第一和
second divs occupy six columns each.
第二个 div 各占据 6 个纵列
And the third one will occupy the entire twelve columns.
而让第三个占据全部 12 个纵列
And the copyright statement I'm going to let that expand the entire twelve columns.
而版权声明 我会让它扩张到全部 12 个纵列
So let me apply those column classes to be as tips and then we'll come back and
让我把这些纵列类应用到这些 div 上 我们再回过头来
look at the completed webpage.
看看整个完成版的网页
I have now completed the changes.
我现在已经完成了所有的变动
Let's go and have a look at the page.
让我们来看一看页面
You can now see how the web page is rendered.
你现在可以看到网页是如何被渲染的
You can see that the jumbotron, the restaurant name and
你可以看到这个Jumbotron
the description is occupying left eight columns.
饭店名和描述占据着左边的 8 个纵列
And then we have empty space here on the right side where the logo will go in
然后右边有空白的位置 稍后我们在这里加上商标
which will be part of the exercise in the next module.
这会是我们下一个模块的练习的一部分
Then, we see that the three pieces of content are now
然后我们看到三大块的内容
laid out such that the headline occupies three columns on the left side.
被布置成标题占据 3 个纵列在左边
And the actual long description occupies the remaining nine columns here.
实际的长描述占据剩余的 9 个纵列放在这里
Going down to that footer, now you can see that the links occupy three columns,
下来到页脚处 你可以看到链接占据了 3 个纵列
the address occupies five columns.
地址占据了 5 个纵列
And then the links our social media sites occupies the remaining four columns here.
然后 指向我们的社交网站的链接占据了剩下的 4 个纵列
The copyright down below here is spanning the entire twelve columns of that row.
下面的版权声明横跨了整行的 12 个纵列
Let us now examine the responsive behavior of this web page.
让我们现在来检查一下网页的响应式行为
Now, taking this web page, let me slowly shrink the web page and see how
现在 开着这个网页 让我慢慢缩小网页的宽度
the webpage responds as the screen size is reduced.
看看网页是如何响应屏幕尺寸的减小的
So this for 1,280 pixels.
现在这是 1280 像素
This is the length of the screen size that I'm using currently.
这是我正在用的屏幕的宽度
I'm gonna keep shrinking the size and you can see the changes in
我会渐渐缩小这个宽度 你就可以看到
the layout of the webpage as I reduce the screen size.
屏幕宽度减小时 网页排版的变化
So this is still for small screen size.
现在这个网页仍然在小尺寸屏幕上
So you can see the layout is still like that, but
你可以看到网页的排版像这样
let's go for the extra small and see what happens.
让我们看看超小屏幕尺寸上会发生什么
Now you can see that when I switch from small to extra small,
现在你可以看到 当我从小尺寸换到超小尺寸时
immediately our content layout changes its behavior.
马上我们的内容排版就发生了改变
So, now I have my description of the restaurant and
现在 饭店的描述还有
the name of the restaurant display occupying the entire screen size.
饭店名称都占据了整个屏幕的宽度
These two items now instead of being side by side now are stacked
原来并排的这两个项目现在变成了
one on top of the other.
上下堆叠
And then look at the footer.
再看一下页脚
You see that the links and address are displayed side by side.
你看到链接和地址现在并排显示
And the links to our social media sites are displayed in a separate
而指向我们的社交网站的链接现在显示在
columns, separate row spanning the entire screen size.
一个单独的行里 占据了整个屏幕的宽度
The copyright remains as such.
版权声明则保持不变
So now you can see how we have introduced responsiveness to our web page.
现在你可以看到我们是如何在我们的网页中引入响应性的
We can see that within the web page, the headline and
我们可以看到在网页中
the description are all laid out in a similar fashion in all the rows.
所有行中的标题和描述都使用了类似的排版方式
Now I wanna make a slight change whereby for
现在我想要做一个细小的改动
some of the rows I want to swap the headline and
让某些行对调标题和描述
the description around specifically for the question in the third row.
特别是第 1 和第 3 行
So that the webpage acquires some more interesting character.
那么这个网页就需要多一些有趣的特性
How do we go about doing that?
我们要怎么做到这一点呢
This is where the push, pull and
这就是我们之前讨论过的
offset classes that we discussed are going to come to our aid.
push, pull 和 offset 等类能够帮上忙的地方了
Let's apply those changes to those classes and then come back and
让我们把这些变化应用到这些类 再回过头来
see the layout of the web page of the point.
看看到时网页排版的变化
For small to large I'm going to push the headline
从小屏到大屏 我会把标题
to the right by nine units,
向右边推 (push) 9 个单位
and pull their description to the left by three units.
然后把描述向左边拉 (pull) 3 个单位
So returning to our HTML page, now for the first and third row,
那么回到我们的 HTML 页面 现在对于第 1 和第 3 行
I'm gonna push the headline to the right, and pull the Description to the left.
我会把标题推向右边 然后把描述拉向左边
So going into the divs, for the headline div I'm going to apply
那么进入到 div 中, 对于标题的 div 我会应用
col-sm-push-9and for
col-sm-push-9
the description I'm going to apply col-sm pull-3.
而对描述的 div 我会应用 col-sm-pull-3
Same thing for the third row too.
对第三行做同样的处理
Going to the footer for the div that shows the links to our webpages,
去页脚 找到装着连到我们的网页的链接的 div
I'm going to apply an offset of one unit to the right and
我要应用1个单位的向右偏移
I'm going to led the two units.
然后让它只占2个单位
So i am going to go in here and I would say,
我会找到这里 然后
col-xs-6, but I will change to col-xs-5.
把 col-xs-6 改为 col-xs-5
And then I will say col-xs-offset-1.
然后再加上 col-xs-offset-1
And col-sm, I'll reduce it to 2.
对于 col-sm 我会把它减少到 2
With this I have updated the class definitions for
做了这些 我就更新了
the links row, links column in my footer.
我的页脚里面的链接列了。
And I'll save the changes and let's go and look at the webpage.
现在让我保存一下这些改动 看看更新的网页
Returning to our webpage, now you see how I have used the push and
回到我们的网页 现在你看到我用了推和拉的类
pull classes to swap things around in the three drawers.
来调整这三行里面的内容的顺序
In the first drawer you can see that the headline has been pushed to right and
在第一行你可以看到标题被推到了右边
the content has been pulled to the left.
而内容则被拉到了左边
And similarly for the third row.
第三行也是类似的情况
Now you can see that the links down below here have been
现在你可以看到下面的这些链接已经
pushed right by one column using the offset.
通过使用偏移(offset)被推向右边一个纵列
The remaining ones stay as such.
其他东西则没有变动
Now if I shrink the webpage to the extra
现在 如果我将网页缩小到超小尺寸
small size, notice that the behavior.
留意一下网页的响应
The layout remains the same as before.
网页的排版跟之前仍然一样
Coming down to the footer I notice that my links are being displayed
翻下来到页脚 我可以看到我的链接
as a bulleted list.
显示为一个点列表
I don't want the bulleted list instead I want to be completely left so
我不想要这个点列表 而想要它完全靠左
to do that I will apply a unstyled list
因此我会应用一个 list-unstyled 类
class to that list and then you will notice the change there.
到这个列表上 然后你就会留意到这里的变动
Going into the code for this UL tag I am going to apply a class
来到这个 ul 标签的源代码 我要应用一个
list-unstyled.
list-unstyled 类
Returning to your webpage you can see now in the footer
回到网页 你可以看到在页脚上
how the links are being displayed without the bullets.
链接列表不再带有点
Next I'm going to show you how we can introduce a custom CSS file
然后我要向你展示我们如何在网站项目中
into our web project.
引入一个自定义的CSS文件
To do that, go to the CSS folder and then introduce a new file there.
要做到这一点 我们来到 CSS 文件夹 在那里创建一个新的文件
And then we will name it as mystyles.css.
然后我们可以叫它mystyles.css
And then when the mystyles.css file is opened,
打来这个mystyles.css文件
I'm going to paste in some CSS code to be
我会粘贴一些CSS代码
applied to some of the elements in my web page.
这些代码会应用到我们网页的某些元素上
So I'll paste in the CSS code which I have provided for you.
粘贴CSS代码 这些代码我会提供给你们
This CSS code, I am making use to style my various rows in the web page.
我使用这些CSS代码来设计网页中各行的样式
In here, you can see that for my header and
在这里 你可以看到我在页首和页尾
my footer I am giving some margin and padding values,
都加了一些 margin 和 padding 的数值
and then similarly for the content rows I am giving some margin and adding values.
对于内容的行 我也添加了类似的 margin 和 padding
In addition, from my content rows,
此外 对于内容行
I am making every content row to be a minimum height of 400 pixels.
我还设置了所有内容行的最小高度为 400 像素
So, this way, our webpage is laid out in a lot more cleaner fashion.
像这样 我们的网页就可以排列得更清晰
For the footer, I will apply a background color of a light gray color there so
对于页脚 我添加了一个浅灰的背景色
that it looks a bit more different from the remaining rows of my web page.
这样它看起来就跟网页的其他部分不一样
After making the changes to the mystyles.css file, I'm gonna save that,
在mystyles.css文件上做了这些改动之后 我会保存它
and then now I need to include the CSS file into my HTML page.
然后把这个CSS文件包含在我的HTML页面里
Moving back to the html code, in the head right
回到HTML代码 在头部(head)
after the import of the bootstrap css files,
紧跟在引入bootstrap文件的后面
I am going to add in one more to import the CSS file that I've just created.
我要多加上一行来引入我们刚刚创建的CSS文件
So I will say css/mystyles.css.
我会写 css/mystyle.css
That's the page that I want to input,
也就是我想引入的文件
and this is a style sheet.
而这是一个样式表文件
So, with that I have included my custom CSS classes into my project.
那么我就把我的自定义CSS类加入到我的项目里来了
Now I can apply those CSS classes to the different rows.
现在我可以把这些CSS类加到不同的行里了
So, let me go ahead and apply those to the header, the content rows.
让我加上这些页首 内容行和页尾的类
And the footer and then we'll see how the webpage has changed.
然后再看看网页有什么变化
So I have applied the header formatting to the row in the header.
我在页首的行里加入了页首的格式
Then I have applied that content row content class
然后在网页的内容部分的行里
to the rows in the content part of our webpage.
加入了 row-content 类
And finally I'm ready to apply the footer content to the row inside my footer.
最后 我要把页尾的格式加入到页尾的行里
Or rather I will apply that directly to the footer itself.
更准确的说把它应用到页尾自身
So now that I have completed applying these classes, let me go back and
这样我就加完了这些类了 让我们回到网页
check that web page and see how it has changed.
检查一下它是如何变化的吧
Returning to your webpage now you can see the webpage layout has changed slightly.
回到网页你会发现网页排版稍微有些变化
The jumbotron remains as such in the header.
在页首 Jumbotron维持不变
Then, but the remaining rules are now occupying a lot more space on the screen.
但是其他的行则占据了比之前多得多的屏幕空间
So since I have declared that the minimum width each row should occupy would
这是因为我给这些行定义了最小高度
be 400 pixels.
为400像素
So the height of each of these rows is now set to 400 pixels.
所以现在这些行 每个的高度都是400像素
The footer has now acquired the gray background color and
而页脚现在则有了灰色的背景色
is displayed at the bottom.
并且在底部显示
Finally, I'll go into my styles.css file and
最后我回到 mystyles.css文件
add in a couple of more custom classes for the jumbotron and
为Jumbotron和页脚的地址
the address that I'm using in the footer.
再加上一些自定义的类
So adding in the code, you see that for
在代码里 你可以看到
the jumbotron, I am setting the padding for the jumbotron appropriately.
我给 Jumbotron 设置了适当的 padding
And also I am going to set the background of the jumbotron to be
此外我还要把 Jumbotron 的背景色设置为
a light indigo color.
浅靛蓝色
And the text to be displayed would be in a off-white color in the jumbotron.
而 Jumbotron 里显示的文字则设置为米白色
The address which appears in the footer of my page.
地址会出现在我们页面的页脚
Now, I'm going to reduce the font size of my address
现在我要减小地址的字号
to be slightly smaller than the standard size.
让它比标准字号略小
It'll be about 80%, so
例如大概标准字号的 80% 左右
that is the modification that I am applying here to that address.
这就是我对地址做出的改动
Switching back to the view of our web page, we now notice
让我们切回网页画面 我们可以看到
that our jumbotron has acquired a light indigo color, and
我们的Jumbotron已经变成了浅靛蓝色
in addition the lettering is now in off-white color in the jumbotron.
此外 Jumbotron 中的文字则变成了米白色
Going down to the footer, you will see that our
然后下来到页脚 你会看到
address is now displayed in a slightly smaller font size than before.
地址现在显示的字号比之前稍微小一些
This completes the modifications that we are going to affect in this exercise.
那么我们在这个练习里面希望做到的改动就全部完成了
At the end of this exercise, we have learned how to apply the column classes
在这个练习的结尾 我们学到了如何将纵列类
to the various divs inside of rows in our webpage.
应用到我们网页中的各种 div 里面
In addition, we have also seen how we can introduce custom CSS classes and
此外 我们还学到了如何引入自定义的CSS类
then apply them to various elements in our webpage.
并且将它们应用到网页中的不同元素上
This concludes this exercise.
这次练习到此结束